

ABOUT

An energetic software engineer with 7+ years experience developing robust applications for high-volume businesses. Experienced working on various projects in differing capacities from industries in Human Resources, Fintech, Healthtech, Telecommunications, High Value Art, and more.

https://emmanuelmichael.com michael.emmanuel732@gmail.com

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Kyndryl (IBM) | Remote Sept 2022 – Current Senior Software Engineer

- Built a serverless and highly scalable ride-sharing application for business client
- Built a fraud detection service for client using code and cloud
- Used Terraform(IaC) to improve collaboration and manage infrastructure

Capital Rx | Remote May 2021 - Aug 2022 Senior Full Stack Developer

- Built a cloud-native enterprise health platform, connecting every aspect of pharmacy ecosystem
- Handled high volumes of data and requests
- Created, tested and maintained REST APIs and handled Protected Health Information (PHI)

CANVII - UpWork | Remote Aug 2020 – May 2021 *Freelance Senior Web Developer*

- Built Social Network eCommerce application to distribute high volumes of art
- Created a product that connects artists to buyers
- Created GraphQL APIs and backend controllers to perform business logic
- Owned scope of project from start to completion

ADP | Remote Feb 2018 – Aug 2020 Application Developer

- Built an all-in-one HR and Financial application
- Handled PII while helping small businesses scale
- Created PCI-DSS compliant event-driven microservices and server-side APIs

Rutgers U. | New Brunswick, NJ Nov 2017 – Jan 2018 Frontend Web Developer

- Converted Rutgers homepage from static web pages to responsive React single page application
- Configured API backend for Rutgers University homepage through RESTful programming

Rutgers Coding Bootcamp Oct 2016 – May 2017 Web Developer Immersive Program

- Contributed to open source
- Built applications for non profit
- Participated in Hackathons

Artsy Jewels | Remote Jan 2016 - Sept 2016 Freelance Web Developer

- Created eCommerce storefront connecting consumers to high value jewelry merchants
- Defined, identified, collected and organized detailed information relating to UI requirements
- Documented new findings and integrations

AT&T Corp | Piscataway, NJ Nov 2014 – Dec 2015 Software Developer in Test (SDET)

- Built automation framework to enhance call center reps view of customer's Test & Turn Up status, allowing for quick and efficient status updates
- Shortened call center conversation durations by 55%

EDUCATION

Rutgers University | New Brunswick, NJ 2010 – 2014 B.S. Computer Science

SKILLS

- Python, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB
- TypeScript, PostgreSQL, SQL, Git, Terraform
- Postman, Figma, VSCode, Linux, Windows
- Docker, GraphQL, Jenkins, AWS, Version ControlPassion for efficiency, AGILE, SCRUM, JIRA
- Excellent and warm communication skills
- Highly organized with strong attention to detail

INTERESTS

- Camera work: Photography & PhotoShop
- Music: Mixing & Mastering
- Hobbies: Gymnastics & Running